hi I'm Bret contas and I wanted to film
a quick video of how I've been uh
performing the rear foot elevated split
squat because I've noticed a couple of
posts in the last couple weeks of people
asking what's the best way to do it
should I have my foot like this or like
this and the general consensus is to to
do it like this but I've been using a
different method over the last couple of
years uh I ration that you know people's
foot falls off they fall off of the
bench sometimes or they just feel
unstable or it can cause a severe
stretch which is you know painful so you
know I ration that the crooks of the
ankle is curved so why not use a curved
surface that'll maximize stability which
maximizes muscle activation that's a
whole other topic but let me show you
what I've been doing so I position a
barbell around knee level I place a
thick bar pad around the barbell and
Hampton makes a really really good one
it's really thick it's it's dense and I
use that same thick bar pad to place
around my hips when I do my my hip list
my shoulder elevated hip or my hip
thrust what I call them but the other
thing I do because if you just use it
this way the barbell would slide around
you'd be unstable again so you have to
secure the barbell in place well I use a
a light band a jump stretch band and I
wrap one end around the barbell wrap it
around the rack and then Loop it again
and I do the same thing the other side
so as you can see this isn't going
anywhere so it stays in place now what I
do
is I unrack the barot off climb
over drap my foot over and
then perform my set and as you can
see
is very very stable and based on the
feedback I've received from athletes and
clients they prefer this method much
more so than this method and they say
I'll never go back to to doing Bulgarian
splots this way again and uh uh one last
thing I wanted to talk about was one of
the posters this week said you know what
what which way maximizes glute
activation and uh in my opinion trying
to maximize your glute activation on a
Bulgarian squat is like trying to find
tun a Ford Pinto when you have a Ferrari
sit in the driveway um this is an
unbelievable if not the best quad
exercise it also increases hamstring
activity over a full squat uh and
decreases back stress but it's not that
good of a glute activ activator in fact
there's there exercis that activate
three to four times as much glute muscle
so do this exercise for the quads do it
to help you know your your jumping power
but for the glutes and for sprinting
exercises that's a whole different
category so anyway I hope you found this
video useful